编号		中文名称																				日文名称																			英文名称
{0x000}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x001}		{一定捕获的宠物球}																		{ポケモンを　かならず　つかまえることが　できる　さいこうの　ボール}				{The best BALL with the ultimate performance. It will catch any wild POKéMON without fail.}
{0x002}		{捕获成功率×2.0的宠物球}																{スーパーボール　より　つかまえ　やすくなった　とても　すごい　ボール}				{A very high-grade BALL that offers a higher POKéMON catch rate than a GREAT BALL.}
{0x003}		{捕获成功率×1.5的宠物球}																{モンスターボール　より　つかまえ　やすくなった　こうせいのうの　ボール}			{A good, quality BALL that offers a higher POKéMON catch rate than a standard POKé BALL.}
{0x004}		{普通的宠物球}																			{やせい　ポケモンを　つかまえるための　どうぐ}										{A BALL thrown to catch a wild POKéMON. It is designed in a capsule style.}
{0x005}		{捕获成功率×1.5的宠物球}																{サファリゾーンで　のみ　つかうことが　できる　とくしゅな　ボール}					{A special BALL that is used only in the SAFARI ZONE. It is finished in a camouflage pattern.}
{0x006}		{对水系、虫系对象，捕获成功率×3.0的宠物球}												{みずと　むしタイプの　ポケモンが　つかまえ　やすくなる　ボール}					{A somewhat different BALL that works especially well on WATER- and BUG-type POKéMON.}
{0x007}		{在水中时，捕获成功率×3.5的宠物球}														{かいていに　いる　ポケモンが　つかまえ　やすくなる　ボール}						{A somewhat different BALL that works especially well on POKéMON deep in the sea.}
{0x008}		{对象的等级不大于30级时，捕获成功率×(40-对象等级)/10的宠物球}							{つかまえる　ポケモンが　よわいほど　つかまえ　やすくなる　ボール}					{A somewhat different BALL that works especially well on weaker POKéMON.}
{0x009}		{对已捕获过的对象，捕获成功率×3.0的宠物球}												{つかまえた　ことが　ある　ポケモンが　つかまえ　やすくなる　ボール}				{A somewhat different BALL that works especially well on POKéMON caught before.}
{0x00A}		{捕获成功率×(回合数+10)/10（但不大于4.0）的宠物球}										{ターンすうが　かかれば　かかるほど　つかまえ　やすくなる　ボール}					{A somewhat different BALL that becomes progressively better the more turns there are in a battle.}
{0x00B}		{每次获得亲密度时，有1点加成的的宠物球}													{つかまえた　ポケモンが　なつき　やすくなる　いごこちの　いい　ボール}				{A comfortable BALL that makes a captured wild POKéMON quickly grow friendly.}
{0x00C}		{珍贵的宠物球}																			{なにかの　きねんに　つくられた　めずらしい　モンスターボール}						{A rare BALL that has been specially made to commemorate an event of some sort.}
{0x00D}		{回复２０点ＨＰ}																		{ポケモンの　たいりょくを　２０　かいふくする}										{A spray-type wound medicine. It restores the HP of one POKéMON by 20 points.}
{0x00E}		{消除中毒状态}																			{どく　じょうたいを　かいふくする}													{A spray-type medicine. It heals one POKéMON from a poisoning.}
{0x00F}		{消除烧伤状态}																			{やけど　じょうたいを　かいふくする}												{A spray-type medicine. It heals one POKéMON of a burn.}
{0x010}		{消除冰冻状态}																			{こおり　じょうたいを　かいふくする}												{A spray-type medicine. It defrosts a frozen POKéMON.}
{0x011}		{消除睡眠状态}																			{ねむり　じょうたいを　かいふくする}												{A spray-type medicine. It awakens a sleeping POKéMON.}
{0x012}		{消除麻痹状态}																			{まひ　じょうたいを　かいふくする}													{A spray-type medicine. It heals one POKéMON from paralysis.}
{0x013}		{回复全部ＨＰ，且消除所有状态异常}														{ポケモンの　たいりょくと　じょうたい　いじょうを　ぜんかいふくする}				{A medicine that fully restores the HP and heals any status problems of one POKéMON.}
{0x014}		{回复全部ＨＰ}																			{ポケモンの　たいりょくを　ぜんかいふくする}										{A spray-type wound medicine. It fully restores the HP of one POKéMON.}
{0x015}		{回复２００点ＨＰ}																		{ポケモンの　たいりょくを　２００　かいふくする}									{A spray-type wound medicine. It restores the HP of one POKéMON by 200 points.}
{0x016}		{回复５０点ＨＰ}																		{ポケモンの　たいりょくを　５０　かいふくする}										{A spray-type wound medicine. It restores the HP of one POKéMON by 50 points.}
{0x017}		{消除所有状态异常}																		{じょうたい　いじょうを　すべて　かいふくする}										{A spray-type medicine. It heals all the status problems of one POKéMON.}
{0x018}		{消除频死状态，回复满ＨＰ的50%}															{ひんし　じょうたいから　たいりょく　はんぶんまで　かいふくする}					{A medicine that revives a fainted POKéMON, restoring HP by half the maximum amount.}
{0x019}		{消除频死状态，回复全部ＨＰ}															{ひんし　じょうたいから　たいりょくを　ぜんかいふくする}							{A medicine that revives a fainted POKéMON, restoring HP fully.}
{0x01A}		{回复５０点ＨＰ}																		{ミネラルたっぷりの　みず　ポケモンの　たいりょくを　５０　かいふくする}			{Water with a high mineral content. It restores the HP of one POKéMON by 50 points.}
{0x01B}		{回复６０点ＨＰ}																		{ジュワーっと　そうかい　ポケモンの　たいりょくを　６０　かいふくする}				{A fizzy soda drink. It restores the HP of one POKéMON by 60 points.}
{0x01C}		{回复８０点ＨＰ}																		{とっても　あまーい　ポケモンの　たいりょくを　８０　かいふくする}					{A very sweet drink. It restores the HP of one POKéMON by 80 points.}
{0x01D}		{回复１００点ＨＰ}																		{えいよう　まんてん　ポケモンの　たいりょくを　１００　かいふくする}				{Highly nutritious milk. It restores the HP of one POKéMON by 100 points.}
{0x01E}		{回复５０点ＨＰ，但降低亲密度５或１０点}												{とても　にがい　こな　ポケモンの　たいりょくを　５０　かいふくする}				{A very bitter medicine powder. It restores the HP of one POKéMON by 50 points.}
{0x01F}		{回复２００点ＨＰ，但降低亲密度１０或１５点}											{とても　にがい　ねっこ　ポケモンの　たいりょくを　２００　かいふくする}			{A very bitter root. It restores the HP of one POKéMON by 200 points.}
{0x020}		{消除所有状态异常，但降低亲密度５或１０点}												{すごく　にがい　こな　じょうたい　いじょうを　すべて　かいふくする}				{A very bitter medicine powder. It heals all the status problems of one POKéMON.}
{0x021}		{消除频死状态，回复全部ＨＰ，但降低亲密度１５或２０点}									{とても　にがい　くさ　ひんし　じょうたいから　ふっかつする}						{A very bitter medicinal herb. It revives a fainted POKéMON, restoring HP fully.}
{0x022}		{对一个技能，回复１０点ＰＰ}															{１つの　わざの　わざポイントを　１０　かいふくする}								{Restores a selected move's PP by 10 points for one POKéMON.}
{0x023}		{对一个技能，回复全部ＰＰ}																{１つの　わざの　わざポイントを　ぜんかいふくする}									{Fully restores a selected move's PP for one POKéMON.}
{0x024}		{对全部技能，各回复１０点ＰＰ}															{すべての　わざの　わざポイントを　１０　かいふくする}								{Restores the PP of all moves for one POKéMON by 10 points each.}
{0x025}		{对全部技能，回复全部ＰＰ}																{ポケモン　１ぴきの　すべての　わざポイントを　ぜんかいふくする}					{Fully restores the PP of all moves for one POKéMON.}
{0x026}		{消除所有状态异常}																		{フエンの　めいぶつ　じょうたい　いじょうを　すべて　かいふくする}					{LAVARIDGE TOWN's local specialty. It heals all the status problems of one POKéMON.}
{0x027}		{消除睡眠状态}																			{ガラスで　できた　ふえ　ねむり　じょうたいを　かいふくする}						{A blue glass flute that awakens a sleeping POKéMON.}
{0x028}		{消除混乱状态}																			{ガラスで　できた　ふえ　こんらん　じょうたいを　かいふくする}						{A yellow glass flute that snaps one POKéMON out of confusion.}
{0x029}		{消除迷惑状态}																			{ガラスで　できた　ふえ　メロメロ　じょうたいを　かいふくする}						{A red glass flute that snaps one POKéMON out of infatuation.}
{0x02A}		{降低随机遇敌的几率（降低的程度依各地区的参数而定）}									{ガラスで　できた　ふえ　やせい　ポケモンと　そうぐう　しにくくなる}				{A black glass flute. When blown, it makes wild POKéMON less likely to appear.}
{0x02B}		{提升随机遇敌的几率（提升的程度依各地区的参数而定）}									{ガラスで　できた　ふえ　やせい　ポケモンと　そうぐう　しやすくなる}				{A white glass flute. When blown, it makes wild POKéMON more likely to appear.}
{0x02C}		{回复２０点ＨＰ}																		{きのみ　１００パーセント　ポケモンの　たいりょくを　２０　かいふくする}			{A 100% pure juice. It restores the HP of one POKéMON by 20 points.}
{0x02D}		{消除频死状态，回复全部ＨＰ}															{ひんししている　ポケモン　すべてを　せいじょうな　じょうたいに　する}				{Revives all fainted POKéMON, restoring HP fully.}
{0x02E}		{看看洞中获得的海盐}																	{あさせのほらあなで　みつけた　しお}												{Pure salt obtained from deep inside the SHOAL CAVE. It is extremely salty.}
{0x02F}		{看看洞中获得的贝壳}																	{あさせのほらあなで　みつけた　かいがら}											{A pretty seashell found deep inside the SHOAL CAVE. It is striped in blue and white.}
{0x030}		{古代物品的碎片，可在１２４号水道的赏金猎人的小屋换取火之石}							{むかしに　つくられた　どうぐの　かけら　らしい　やすく　うれる}					{A small red shard. It appears to be from some sort of a tool made long ago.}
{0x031}		{古代物品的碎片，可在１２４号水道的赏金猎人的小屋换取水之石}							{むかしに　つくられた　どうぐの　かけら　らしい　やすく　うれる}					{A small blue shard. It appears to be from some sort of a tool made long ago.}
{0x032}		{古代物品的碎片，可在１２４号水道的赏金猎人的小屋换取雷之石}							{むかしに　つくられた　どうぐの　かけら　らしい　やすく　うれる}					{A small yellow shard. It appears to be from some sort of a tool made long ago.}
{0x033}		{古代物品的碎片，可在１２４号水道的赏金猎人的小屋换取叶之石}							{むかしに　つくられた　どうぐの　かけら　らしい　やすく　うれる}					{A small green shard. It appears to be from some sort of a tool made long ago.}
{0x034}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x035}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x036}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x037}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x038}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x039}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x03A}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x03B}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x03C}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x03D}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x03E}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x03F}		{ＨＰ努力值增加１０点（１００点或以上时无效）}											{たいりょくの　きそポイントを　あげる}												{A nutritious drink for POKéMON. It raises the base HP of one POKéMON.}
{0x040}		{攻击努力值增加１０点（１００点或以上时无效）}											{こうげきの　きそポイントを　あげる}												{A nutritious drink for POKéMON. It raises the base ATTACK stat of one POKéMON.}
{0x041}		{防御努力值增加１０点（１００点或以上时无效）}											{ぼうぎょの　きそポイントを　あげる}												{A nutritious drink for POKéMON. It raises the base DEFENSE stat of one POKéMON.}
{0x042}		{敏捷努力值增加１０点（１００点或以上时无效）}											{すばやさの　きそポイントを　あげる}												{A nutritious drink for POKéMON. It raises the base SPEED stat of one POKéMON.}
{0x043}		{特攻努力值增加１０点（１００点或以上时无效）}											{とくこうの　きそポイントを　あげる}												{A nutritious drink for POKéMON. It raises the base SP. ATK stat of one POKéMON.}
{0x044}		{等级提升１级}																			{ポケモンの　レベルを　１　あげる}													{A candy that is packed with energy. It raises the level of a POKéMON by one.}
{0x045}		{对一个技能，ＰＰ最大值增加基础值的20%（最大60%）}										{わざポイントの　さいだいちが　あがる}												{Slightly raises the maximum PP of a selected move for one POKéMON.}
{0x046}		{特防努力值增加１０点（１００点或以上时无效）}											{とくぼうの　きそポイントを　あげる}												{A nutritious drink for POKéMON. It raises the base SP. DEF stat of one POKéMON.}
{0x047}		{对一个技能，ＰＰ最大值增加到最大（基础值的160%）}										{わざポイントを　さいだいちまで　あげる}											{Raises the PP of a selected move to its maximum level for one POKéMON.}
{0x048}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x049}		{战斗中使用，５回合内，本方的宠物的能力等级不会被降低}									{せんとうで　つかうと　みかたの　のうりょくを　さげられなくする}					{An item that prevents stat reduction among party POKéMON for five turns after use.}
{0x04A}		{战斗中使用，会心一击率升１级}															{つかった　せんとうちゅう　あいての　きゅうしょに　あたりやすくなる}				{Raises the critical-hit ratio of POKéMON in battle. Wears off if the POKéMON is withdrawn.}
{0x04B}		{战斗中使用，攻击升１级}																{つかった　せんとうちゅう　こうげきりょくが　あがる}								{Raises the ATTACK stat of POKéMON in battle. Wears off if the POKéMON is withdrawn.}
{0x04C}		{战斗中使用，防御升１级}																{つかった　せんとうちゅう　ぼうぎょりょくが　あがる}								{Raises the DEFENSE stat of POKéMON in battle. Wears off if the POKéMON is withdrawn.}
{0x04D}		{战斗中使用，敏捷升１级}																{つかった　せんとうちゅう　すばやさが　あがる}										{Raises the SPEED stat of POKéMON in battle. Wears off if the POKéMON is withdrawn.}
{0x04E}		{战斗中使用，命中率升１级}																{つかった　せんとうちゅう　わざが　あたりやすくなる}								{Raises the accuracy stat of POKéMON in battle. Wears off if the POKéMON is withdrawn.}
{0x04F}		{战斗中使用，特攻升１级}																{つかった　せんとうちゅう　とくこうの　いりょくが　あがる}							{Raises the SP. ATK stat of POKéMON in battle. Wears off if the POKéMON is withdrawn.}
{0x050}		{从随机遇敌战斗中逃跑}																	{そうぐうした　やせいの　ポケモンから　かならず　にげることが　できる}				{An attractive doll. Use it to flee from any battle with a wild POKéMON.}
{0x051}		{从随机遇敌战斗中逃跑}																	{そうぐうした　やせいの　ポケモンから　かならず　にげることが　できる}				{An attractive item. Use it to flee from any battle with a wild POKéMON.}
{0x052}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x053}		{２００步之内，不会遇到等级低于队首宠物等级的野生宠物}									{２００ぽ　すすむ　あいだ　よわい　ポケモンと　そうぐう　しなくなる}				{Prevents weak wild POKéMON from appearing for 200 steps.}
{0x054}		{２５０步之内，不会遇到等级低于队首宠物等级的野生宠物}									{２５０ぽ　すすむ　あいだ　よわい　ポケモンと　そうぐう　しなくなる}				{Prevents weak wild POKéMON from appearing for 250 steps.}
{0x055}		{洞穴、建筑物中使用，直接回到进来的入口处}												{どうくつや　ダンジョンを　ぬけだせる}												{A long, durable rope. Use it to escape instantly from a cave or a dungeon.}
{0x056}		{１００步之内，不会遇到等级低于队首宠物等级的野生宠物}									{１００ぽ　すすむ　あいだ　よわい　ポケモンと　そうぐう　しなくなる}				{Prevents weak wild POKéMON from appearing for 100 steps.}
{0x057}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x058}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x059}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x05A}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x05B}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x05C}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x05D}		{进化石之一}																			{とくていの　ポケモンを　しんかさせる}												{A peculiar stone that makes certain species of POKéMON evolve. It is as red as the sun.}
{0x05E}		{进化石之一}																			{とくていの　ポケモンを　しんかさせる}												{A peculiar stone that makes certain species of POKéMON evolve. It is as black as the night sky.}
{0x05F}		{进化石之一}																			{とくていの　ポケモンを　しんかさせる}												{A peculiar stone that makes certain species of POKéMON evolve. It is colored orange.}
{0x060}		{进化石之一}																			{とくていの　ポケモンを　しんかさせる}												{A peculiar stone that makes certain species of POKéMON evolve. It has a thunderbolt pattern.}
{0x061}		{进化石之一}																			{とくていの　ポケモンを　しんかさせる}												{A peculiar stone that makes certain species of POKéMON evolve. It is a clear light blue.}
{0x062}		{进化石之一}																			{とくていの　ポケモンを　しんかさせる}												{A peculiar stone that makes certain species of POKéMON evolve. It has a leaf pattern.}
{0x063}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x064}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x065}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x066}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x067}		{用于２岛的技能屋，使宠物学会自己的升级技能}											{ふつうの　キノコ　やすく　うれる}													{A small and rare mushroom. It is quite popular among certain people.}
{0x068}		{用于２岛的技能屋，使宠物学会自己的升级技能}											{めずらしい　キノコ　たかく　うれる}												{A large and rare mushroom. It is very popular among certain people.}
{0x069}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x06A}		{售价高}																				{きれいな　しんじゅ　やすく　うれる}												{A relatively small pearl that sparkles in a pretty silver color. It can be sold cheaply.}
{0x06B}		{售价高}																				{とても　きれいな　おおつぶの　しんじゅ　たかく　うれる}							{A quite-large pearl that sparkles in a pretty silver color. It can be sold at a high price.}
{0x06C}		{售价高}																				{あかくて　きれいな　すな　たかく　うれる}											{A pretty red sand with a loose, silky feel. It can be sold at a high price.}
{0x06D}		{售价高}																				{あかくて　きれいな　ほうせきの　かけら　とても　たかく　うれる}					{A shard of a pretty gem that sparkles in a red color. It can be sold at a high price.}
{0x06E}		{售价高}																				{じゅんきん　せい　たかく　うれる}													{A nugget of pure gold that gives off a lustrous gleam. It can be sold at a high price.}
{0x06F}		{用于哈吉镇的教学屋，使宠物学会自己的升级技能}											{きれいな　ウロコ　マニアの　あいだで　にんきが　たかい}							{A pretty, heart-shaped scale that is extremely rare. It glows faintly in the colors of a rainbow.}
{0x070}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x071}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x072}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x073}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x074}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x075}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x076}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x077}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x078}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x079}		{画有针鼠的信封}																		{ジグザグマの　すがたが　プリントされた　びんせん　ポケモンに　もたせる}			{A piece of MAIL featuring a cute ZIGZAGOON print. It is to be held by a POKéMON.}
{0x07A}		{画有海鸥的信封}																		{キャモメの　すがたが　プリントされた　びんせん　ポケモンに　もたせる}				{A piece of MAIL featuring a cute WINGULL print. It is to be held by a POKéMON.}
{0x07B}		{画有皮卡丘的信封}																		{ピカチュウの　すがたが　プリントされた　びんせん　ポケモンに　もたせる}			{A piece of MAIL featuring a cute PIKACHU print. It is to be held by a POKéMON.}
{0x07C}		{画有小磁怪的信封}																		{コイルの　すがたが　プリントされた　びんせん　ポケモンに　もたせる}				{A piece of MAIL featuring a cute MAGNEMITE print. It is to be held by a POKéMON.}
{0x07D}		{画有小懒猴的信封}																		{ナマケロの　すがたが　プリントされた　びんせん　ポケモンに　もたせる}				{A piece of MAIL featuring a cute SLAKOTH print. It is to be held by a POKéMON.}
{0x07E}		{画有皮皮鲸的信封}																		{ホエルコの　すがたが　プリントされた　びんせん　ポケモンに　もたせる}				{A piece of MAIL featuring a cute WAILMER print. It is to be held by a POKéMON.}
{0x07F}		{画有手持该信封的宠物的印记的信封}														{もたせた　ポケモンの　にがおえがでる　びんせん}									{A piece of MAIL to be held by a POKéMON. It will bear the print of the POKéMON holding it.}
{0x080}		{画有钻墙鬼的信封}																		{ヨマワルの　すがたが　プリントされた　びんせん　ポケモンに　もたせる}				{A piece of MAIL featuring a cute DUSKULL print. It is to be held by a POKéMON.}
{0x081}		{画有美丽花的信封}																		{キレイハナの　すがたが　プリントされた　びんせん　ポケモンに　もたせる}			{A piece of MAIL featuring a cute BELLOSSOM print. It is to be held by a POKéMON.}
{0x082}		{画有手持该信封的宠物的印记的信封}														{もたせた　ポケモンの　にがおえがでる　びんせん}									{A piece of MAIL to be held by a POKéMON. It will bear the print of the POKéMON holding it.}
{0x083}		{画有华丽纹彩的信封}																	{ごうかな　もようが　プリントされた　びんせん　ポケモンに　もたせる}				{A piece of MAIL featuring a gorgeous, extravagant print. It is to be held by a POKéMON.}
{0x084}		{画有３种不同宠物的信封}																{３ひきの　ポケモンが　プリントされた　びんせん　ポケモンに　もたせる}				{A piece of MAIL featuring a print of three cute POKéMON. It is to be held by a POKéMON.}
{0x085}		{手持道具，消耗品，消除麻痹状态}														{もたせると　じぶんで　まひ　じょうたいを　かいふくする}							{When held by a POKéMON, it will be used in battle to heal paralysis.}
{0x086}		{手持道具，消耗品，消除睡眠状态}														{もたせると　じぶんで　ねむり　じょうたいを　かいふくする}							{When held by a POKéMON, it will be used in battle to wake up.}
{0x087}		{手持道具，消耗品，消除中毒状态}														{もたせると　じぶんで　どく　じょうたいを　かいふくする}							{When held by a POKéMON, it will be used in battle to cure poison.}
{0x088}		{手持道具，消耗品，消除烧伤状态}														{もたせると　じぶんで　やけど　じょうたいを　かいふくする}							{When held by a POKéMON, it will be used in battle to heal a burn.}
{0x089}		{手持道具，消耗品，消除冰冻状态}														{もたせると　じぶんで　こおり　じょうたいを　かいふくする}							{When held by a POKéMON, it will be used in battle for defrosting.}
{0x08A}		{手持道具，消耗品，对一个技能，回复１０点ＰＰ}											{もたせると　じぶんで　わざポイントを　１０　かいふくする}							{When held by a POKéMON, it will be used in battle to restore 10 PP.}
{0x08B}		{手持道具，消耗品，回复１０点ＨＰ}														{もたせると　じぶんで　たいりょくを　１０　かいふくする}							{When held by a POKéMON, it will be used in battle to restore 10 HP.}
{0x08C}		{手持道具，消耗品，消除混乱状态}														{もたせると　じぶんで　こんらん　じょうたいを　かいふくする}						{When held by a POKéMON, it will be used in battle to lift confusion.}
{0x08D}		{手持道具，消耗品，消除所有状态异常}													{もたせると　じぶんで　じょうたい　いじょうを　かいふくする}						{When held by a POKéMON, it will be used in battle to heal any problem.}
{0x08E}		{手持道具，消耗品，回复３０点ＨＰ}														{もたせると　じぶんで　たいりょくを　３０　かいふくする}							{When held by a POKéMON, it will be used in battle to restore 30 HP.}
{0x08F}		{手持道具，消耗品，回复ＨＰ，但可能会混乱}												{もたせると　たいりょくを　かいふく　できるが　こんらんする　ことがある}			{A hold item that restores HP but may cause confusion when used.}
{0x090}		{手持道具，消耗品，回复ＨＰ，但可能会混乱}												{もたせると　たいりょくを　かいふく　できるが　こんらんする　ことがある}			{A hold item that restores HP but may cause confusion when used.}
{0x091}		{手持道具，消耗品，回复ＨＰ，但可能会混乱}												{もたせると　たいりょくを　かいふく　できるが　こんらんする　ことがある}			{A hold item that restores HP but may cause confusion when used.}
{0x092}		{手持道具，消耗品，回复ＨＰ，但可能会混乱}												{もたせると　たいりょくを　かいふく　できるが　こんらんする　ことがある}			{A hold item that restores HP but may cause confusion when used.}
{0x093}		{手持道具，消耗品，回复ＨＰ，但可能会混乱}												{もたせると　たいりょくを　かいふく　できるが　こんらんする　ことがある}			{A hold item that restores HP but may cause confusion when used.}
{0x094}		{美容糖果的材料}																		{ポロックの　ざいりょう　つちのなかに　うめると　ズリが　そだつ}					{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x095}		{美容糖果的材料}																		{ポロックの　ざいりょう　つちのなかに　うめると　ブリーが　そだつ}					{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x096}		{美容糖果的材料}																		{ポロックの　ざいりょう　つちのなかに　うめると　ナナが　そだつ}					{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x097}		{美容糖果的材料}																		{ポロックの　ざいりょう　つちのなかに　うめると　セシナが　そだつ}					{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x098}		{美容糖果的材料}																		{ポロックの　ざいりょう　つちのなかに　うめると　パイルが　そだつ}					{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x099}		{增加３或６点亲密度，但降低ＨＰ努力值１０点（仅宝石版）}								{ポケモンが　ちょっと　なつくが　ＨＰの　きそポイントが　さがる}					{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x09A}		{增加３或６点亲密度，但降低攻击努力值１０点（仅宝石版）}								{ポケモンが　ちょっと　なつくが　こうげきの　きそポイントが　さがる}				{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x09B}		{增加３或６点亲密度，但降低防御努力值１０点（仅宝石版）}								{ポケモンが　ちょっと　なつくが　ぼうぎょの　きそポイントが　さがる}				{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x09C}		{增加３或６点亲密度，但降低特攻努力值１０点（仅宝石版）}								{ポケモンが　ちょっと　なつくが　とくこうの　きそポイントが　さがる}				{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x09D}		{增加３或６点亲密度，但降低特防努力值１０点（仅宝石版）}								{ポケモンが　ちょっと　なつくが　とくぼうの　きそポイントが　さがる}				{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x09E}		{增加３或６点亲密度，但降低敏捷努力值１０点（仅宝石版）}								{ポケモンが　ちょっと　なつくが　すばやさの　きそポイントが　さがる}				{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x09F}		{美容糖果的材料}																		{ポロックの　ざいりょう　つちのなかに　うめると　モコシが　そだつ}					{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x0A0}		{美容糖果的材料}																		{ポロックの　ざいりょう　つちのなかに　うめると　ゴスが　そだつ}					{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x0A1}		{美容糖果的材料}																		{ポロックの　ざいりょう　つちのなかに　うめると　ラブタが　そだつ}					{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x0A2}		{美容糖果的材料}																		{ポロックの　ざいりょう　つちのなかに　うめると　ノメルが　そだつ}					{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x0A3}		{美容糖果的材料}																		{ポロックの　ざいりょう　つちのなかに　うめると　ノワキが　そだつ}					{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x0A4}		{美容糖果的材料}																		{ポロックの　ざいりょう　つちのなかに　うめると　シーヤが　そだつ}					{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x0A5}		{美容糖果的材料}																		{ポロックの　ざいりょう　つちのなかに　うめると　カイスが　そだつ}					{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x0A6}		{美容糖果的材料}																		{ポロックの　ざいりょう　つちのなかに　うめると　ドリが　そだつ}					{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x0A7}		{美容糖果的材料}																		{ポロックの　ざいりょう　つちのなかに　うめると　ベリブが　そだつ}					{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x0A8}		{手持道具，消耗品，频死的时候，攻击升１级}												{もたせると　ピンチのとき　こうげきりょくが　あがる}								{When held by a POKéMON, it raises the ATTACK stat in a pinch.}
{0x0A9}		{手持道具，消耗品，频死的时候，防御升１级}												{もたせると　ピンチのとき　ぼうぎょりょくが　あがる}								{When held by a POKéMON, it raises the DEFENSE stat in a pinch.}
{0x0AA}		{手持道具，消耗品，频死的时候，敏捷升１级}												{もたせると　ピンチのとき　すばやさが　あがる}										{When held by a POKéMON, it raises the SPEED stat in a pinch.}
{0x0AB}		{手持道具，消耗品，频死的时候，特攻升１级}												{もたせると　ピンチのとき　とくこうが　あがる}										{When held by a POKéMON, it raises the SP. ATK stat in a pinch.}
{0x0AC}		{手持道具，消耗品，频死的时候，特防升１级}												{もたせると　ピンチのとき　とくぼうが　あがる}										{When held by a POKéMON, it raises the SP. DEF stat in a pinch.}
{0x0AD}		{手持道具，频死的时候，会心一击率升１级}												{もたせると　ピンチのとき　てきの　きゅうしょに　あたり　やすくなる}				{When held by a POKéMON, it raises the critical-hit ratio in a pinch.}
{0x0AE}		{手持道具，消耗品，ＨＰ低于满值的1/3时，某一项能力升２级}								{もたせると　ピンチのとき　のうりょくの　どれか　１つが　ぐーんと　あがる}			{When held by a POKéMON, it sharply raises one stat in a pinch.}
{0x0AF}		{美容糖果的材料}																		{ポロックの　ざいりょう　つちのなかに　うめると　なぞな　みが　そだつ}				{Can be ground up into a powder as an ingredient for medicine.}
{0x0B0}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0B1}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0B2}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0B3}		{手持道具，对手的命中率×0.9倍}															{もたせると　ひかりが　あいてを　まどわして　めいちゅうりつを　さげる}				{An item to be held by a POKéMON. It casts a tricky glare that lowers the opponent's accuracy.}
{0x0B4}		{手持道具，消耗品，回复被降低的能力值等级}												{ポケモンに　もたせると　さがった　のうりょくを　もとにもどす}						{An item to be held by a POKéMON. It restores any lowered stat in battle. It can be used only once.}
{0x0B5}		{手持道具，获取的努力值×２，但自身速度降１级}											{ポケモンに　もたせると　すばやさが　さがるが　　つよく　そだつ}					{An item to be held by a POKéMON. It promotes strong growth but lowers SPEED while it is held.}
{0x0B6}		{手持道具，战斗所获得的经验值增加１倍，这１倍的经验值被持有者平分}						{もたせた　ポケモンが　けいけんちを　わけて　もらえる}								{An item to be held by a POKéMON. The holder gets a share of EXP. points without having to battle.}
{0x0B7}		{手持道具，有机会优先发出技能}															{ポケモンに　もたせると　せんせい　こうげきが　たまに　できる}						{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A light and sharp claw. The holder may be able to strike first.}
{0x0B8}		{手持道具，获得的亲密度×1.5倍}															{もたせると　ポケモンが　とっても　やすらいで　　なつき　やすくなる}				{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A bell with a comforting chime that makes the holder calm and friendly.}
{0x0B9}		{手持道具，消耗品，消除迷惑状态}														{もたせた　ポケモンが　メロメロに　なったとき　なおして　くれる}					{An item to be held by a POKéMON. It snaps the holder out of infatuation. It can be used once.}
{0x0BA}		{手持道具，战斗中只能使用一个技能，该技能威力增加，但是无法使用其它技能}				{こうげきの　いりょくが　あがるが　おなじ　わざしか　だせなくなる}					{An item to be held by a POKéMON. It powers up one move, which becomes the only usable one.}
{0x0BB}		{手持道具，有机会使被命中的敌人害怕}													{ポケモンに　もたせると　ダメージを　うけた　あいてが　たまに　ひるむ}				{An item to be held by a POKéMON. It may cause the foe to flinch upon taking damage.}
{0x0BC}		{手持道具，虫系技能的威力×1.1倍}														{ポケモンに　もたせると　むしタイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}					{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A shiny silver powder that boosts the power of BUG-type moves.}
{0x0BD}		{手持道具，若持有者上过场，则战斗所获得的奖金×2倍}										{もたせた　ポケモンが　せんとうに　でると　おかねが　２ばいもらえる}				{An item to be held by a POKéMON. It doubles the battle money if the holding POKéMON takes part.}
{0x0BE}		{手持道具，若持有者排在队首，则降低随机遇敌的几率（降低的程度依各地区的参数而定）}		{ポケモンに　もたせると　やせいの　ポケモンに　そうぐう　しにくく　なる}			{An item to be held by a POKéMON. It repels wild POKéMON if the holder is first in the party.}
{0x0BF}		{手持道具，若红水都或蓝水都持有，则其特攻和特防×1.5倍（战斗塔中无效）}					{ラティオス　ラティアスに　もたせると　とくこうと　とくぼうが　あがる}				{An orb to be held by a LATIOS or LATIAS. It raises the SP. ATK and SP. DEF stats.}
{0x0C0}		{手持道具，若海贝持有，则其特攻×2倍}													{するどく　ひかる　キバ　パールルに　もたせると　とくこうが　あがる}				{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A fang that gleams a sharp silver. It raises the SP. ATK stat.}
{0x0C1}		{手持道具，若海贝持有，则其特防×2倍}													{にぶく　ひかる　ウロコ　パールルに　もたせると　とくぼうが　あがる}				{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A scale that shines a faint pink. It raises the SP. DEF stat.}
{0x0C2}		{手持道具，持有者一定能够从随机遇敌战斗中逃跑}											{そうぐうした　やせいの　ポケモンから　かならず　にげられる}						{An item to be held by a POKéMON. The holding POKéMON can flee from any wild POKéMON for sure.}
{0x0C3}		{手持道具，持有者不能进化；绿宝石中母方/百变怪持有，则遗传持有者的性格给后代}			{もたせた　ポケモンが　しんか　しなくなる　ふしぎな　いし}							{An item to be held by a POKéMON. The holding POKéMON is prevented from evolving.}
{0x0C4}		{手持道具，持有者战斗不能时，有机会获得１点ＨＰ而继续战斗}								{ポケモンに　もたせると　たまに　ひんしを　ふせぐことが　できる}					{An item to be held by a POKéMON. The holding POKéMON may endure an attack, leaving just 1 HP.}
{0x0C5}		{手持道具，持有者获得的经验值×1.5倍（在学习装置的计算之后）}							{もたせた　ポケモンの　けいけんちが　いつもより　おおめに　もらえる}				{An item to be held by a POKéMON. An egg filled with happiness that earns extra EXP. points in battle.}
{0x0C6}		{手持道具，持有者的会心一击率升１级}													{ポケモンに　もたせると　きゅうしょに　あたり　やすくなる}							{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A lens that boosts the critical-hit ratio of the holding POKéMON.}
{0x0C7}		{手持道具，钢系技能的威力×1.1倍}														{ポケモンに　もたせると　はがねタイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}					{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A special metallic film that boosts the power of STEEL-type moves.}
{0x0C8}		{手持道具，持有者每回合回复满ＨＰ的1/16}												{もたせると　たいりょくが　せんとうの　あいだ　すこしずつ　かいふくする}			{An item to be held by a POKéMON. The holding POKéMON gradually regains HP during battle.}
{0x0C9}		{手持道具，若海刺龙在通信交换时持有，则升级为海马龙}									{ドラゴンタイプの　ポケモンが　もっている　ふしぎな　ウロコ}						{A thick and tough scale. A DRAGON-type POKéMON may be holding it.}
{0x0CA}		{手持道具，若皮卡丘持有，则其特攻×2倍}													{ビリビリしている　たま　ピカチュウに　もたせると　とくこうが　あがる}				{An orb to be held by a PIKACHU that raises the SP. ATK stat. Touching it may cause a shock.}
{0x0CB}		{手持道具，地面系技能威力×1.1倍}														{ポケモンに　もたせると　じめんタイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}					{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A loose, silky sand that boosts the power of GROUND-type moves.}
{0x0CC}		{手持道具，岩系技能威力×1.1倍}															{ポケモンに　もたせると　いわタイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}					{An item to be held by a POKéMON. An unbreakable stone that boosts the power of ROCK-type moves.}
{0x0CD}		{手持道具，草系技能威力×1.1倍}															{ポケモンに　もたせると　くさタイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}					{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A seed imbued with life that boosts the power of GRASS-type moves.}
{0x0CE}		{手持道具，恶系技能威力×1.1倍}															{ポケモンに　もたせると　あくタイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}					{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A shady-looking pair of glasses that boosts DARK-type moves.}
{0x0CF}		{手持道具，格斗系技能威力×1.1倍}														{ポケモンに　もたせると　かくとうタイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}				{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A belt that boosts determination and FIGHTING-type moves.}
{0x0D0}		{手持道具，电系技能威力×1.1倍}															{ポケモンに　もたせると　でんきタイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}					{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A powerful magnet that boosts the power of ELECTRIC-type moves.}
{0x0D1}		{手持道具，水系技能威力×1.1倍}															{ポケモンに　もたせると　みずタイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}					{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A teardrop-shaped gem that boosts the power of WATER-type moves.}
{0x0D2}		{手持道具，飞行系技能威力×1.1倍}														{ポケモンに　もたせると　ひこうタイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}					{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A long, sharp beak that boosts the power of FLYING-type moves.}
{0x0D3}		{手持道具，毒系技能威力×1.1倍}															{ポケモンに　もたせると　どくタイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}					{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A small, poisonous barb that boosts the power of POISON-type moves.}
{0x0D4}		{手持道具，冰系技能威力×1.1倍}															{ポケモンに　もたせると　こおりタイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}					{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A piece of ice that repels heat and boosts ICE-type moves.}
{0x0D5}		{手持道具，鬼系技能威力×1.1倍}															{ポケモンに　もたせると　ゴーストタイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}				{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A sinister, eerie tag that boosts GHOST-type moves.}
{0x0D6}		{手持道具，超能系技能威力×1.1倍}														{ポケモンに　もたせると　エスパータイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}				{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A spoon imbued with telekinetic power boosts PSYCHIC-type moves.}
{0x0D7}		{手持道具，炎系技能威力×1.1倍}															{ポケモンに　もたせると　ほのおタイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}					{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A combustible fuel that boosts the power of FIRE-type moves.}
{0x0D8}		{手持道具，龙系技能威力×1.1倍}															{ポケモンに　もたせると　ドラゴンタイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}				{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A hard and sharp fang that boosts the power of DRAGON-type moves.}
{0x0D9}		{手持道具，普通系技能威力×1.1倍}														{ポケモンに　もたせると　ノーマルタイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}				{An item to be held by a POKéMON. A sumptuous scarf that boosts the power of NORMAL-type moves.}
{0x0DA}		{手持道具，若3D龙在通信交换时持有，则升级为3D龙2}										{ふしぎな　はこ　シルフ　カンパニーせい}											{A transparent device filled with all sorts of data. It is made by SILPH CO.}
{0x0DB}		{手持道具，对敌造成伤害值的一部分，将用于回复持有者的ＨＰ}								{もたせると　てきに　ダメージを　あたえたとき　たいりょくが　かいふく}				{An item to be held by a POKéMON. The holding POKéMON regains some HP upon striking the foe.}
{0x0DC}		{手持道具，水系技能威力×1.05倍}														{ポケモンに　もたせると　すこしだけ　みずタイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}		{An item to be held by a POKéMON. It slightly boosts the power of WATER-type moves.}
{0x0DD}		{手持道具，对手的命中率×0.95倍}														{ポケモンに　もたせると　てきの　めいちゅうりつを　すこしだけ　さげる}				{An item to be held by a POKéMON. Its tricky aroma slightly reduces the foe's accuracy.}
{0x0DE}		{手持道具，若吉利蛋持有，则其会心一击率升２级}											{ラッキーに　もたせると　あいての　きゅうしょに　あたりやすくなる}					{A glove to be held by a CHANSEY. It raises CHANSEY's critical-hit ratio.}
{0x0DF}		{手持道具，若百变怪持有，则其防御×2倍}													{メタモンに　もたせると　ぼうぎょが　あがる}										{A fine, hard powder to be held by a DITTO. It raises DITTO's DEFENSE stat.}
{0x0E0}		{手持道具，若可拉可拉或嘎拉嘎拉持有，则其攻击×2倍}										{カラカラや　ガラガラに　もたせると　こうげきの　いりょくが　あがる}				{A hard bone of some sort to be held by a CUBONE or MAROWAK. It raises the ATTACK stat.}
{0x0E1}		{手持道具，若大葱鸭持有，则其会心一击率升２级}											{カモネギに　もたせると　きゅうしょに　あたりやすくなる}							{A stick of leek to be held by a FARFETCH'D. It raises FARFETCH'D's critical-hit ratio.}
{0x0E2}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0E3}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0E4}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0E5}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0E6}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0E7}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0E8}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0E9}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0EA}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0EB}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0EC}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0ED}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0EE}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0EF}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0F0}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0F1}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0F2}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0F3}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0F4}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0F5}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0F6}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0F7}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0F8}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0F9}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0FA}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0FB}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0FC}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0FD}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x0FE}		{手持道具，持有者在选美赛上变得更帅气}													{もたせて　コンテストに　さんかすると　いつもより　かっこよく　みられる}			{An item to be held by a POKéMON. It boosts the holding POKéMON's COOL condition in CONTESTS.}
{0x0FF}		{手持道具，持有者在选美赛上变得更美丽}													{もたせて　コンテストに　さんかすると　いつもより　うつくしく　みられる}			{An item to be held by a POKéMON. It boosts the holding POKéMON's BEAUTY condition in CONTESTS.}
{0x100}		{手持道具，持有者在选美赛上变得更可爱}													{もたせて　コンテストに　さんかすると　いつもより　かわいく　みられる}				{An item to be held by a POKéMON. It boosts the holding POKéMON's CUTE condition in CONTESTS.}
{0x101}		{手持道具，持有者在选美赛上变得更聪明}													{もたせて　コンテストに　さんかすると　いつもより　かしこく　みられる}				{An item to be held by a POKéMON. It boosts the holding POKéMON's SMART condition in CONTESTS.}
{0x102}		{手持道具，持有者在选美赛上变得更坚强}													{もたせて　コンテストに　さんかすると　いつもより　たくましく　みられる}			{An item to be held by a POKéMON. It boosts the holding POKéMON's TOUGH condition in CONTESTS.}
{0x103}		{可加速到通常速率２倍的折叠式自行车}													{２ばい　いじょうの　はやさで　いどう　できる　おりたたみの　じてんしゃ}			{A folding bicycle that is at least twice as fast as walking.}
{0x104}		{可存放９９９９枚游戏币的盒子}															{てにいれた　コインを　９９９９まい　まで　もつことが　できる}						{A case for holding COINS obtained at the GAME CORNER. It holds up to 9,999 COINS.}
{0x105}		{通过声音反映隐藏的道具位置的机器}														{みえない　どうぐに　はんのうして　おとで　おしえて　くれる}						{A device used for finding items. If there is a hidden item nearby when it is used, it emits a signal.}
{0x106}		{渔具}																					{ポケモンを　つるどうぐ　みずべで　つかうと　ポケモンが　つれる}					{An old and beat-up fishing rod. Use it by any body of water to fish for wild POKéMON.}
{0x107}		{不错的渔具}																			{ポケモンを　つるどうぐ　なかなかの　つりざおと　いわれている}						{A new, good-quality fishing rod. Use it by any body of water to fish for wild POKéMON.}
{0x108}		{最好的渔具}																			{ポケモンを　つるどうぐ　さいこうの　つりざおと　いわれている}						{An awesome, high-tech fishing rod. Use it by any body of water to fish for wild POKéMON.}
{0x109}		{使用联络船的必需品}																	{れんらくせんに　のるとき　ひつよう}												{The ticket required for sailing on the ferry S.S. ANNE. It has a drawing of a ship on it.}
{0x10A}		{参加选美赛的证件}																		{ポケモンコンテストに　さんかする　ことができる}									{The pass required for entering POKéMON CONTESTS. It has a drawing of an award ribbon on it.}
{0x10B}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x10C}		{种植树果时，用来浇水的用具}															{みずを　かける　どうぐ　つちに　うめた　きのみを　すくすく　そだてる}				{A nifty watering pail. Use it to promote strong growth in BERRIES planted in soft soil.}
{0x10D}		{德邦制造的行李箱，里面装着零件}														{デボンで　つくられた　なにかの　パーツが　はいっている　にもつ}					{A package that contains mechanical parts of some sort made by the DEVON CORPORATION.}
{0x10E}		{用来收集火山灰的袋子}																	{つもった　かざんばいを　あつめるための　ふくろ}									{A sack used to collect volcanic ash automatically during walks over deep ash.}
{0x10F}		{进入金叶市地下的新金叶发电厂的钥匙}													{キンセツの　ちかにある　ニューキンセツに　はいる　ための　カギ}					{The key to NEW MAUVILLE, which was constructed beneath MAUVILLE CITY.}
{0x110}		{可以跳跃和提轮的折叠式自行车}															{ジャンプや　ウイリーの　アクションが　できる　おりたたみの　じてんしゃ}			{A folding bicycle that is capable of stunts like jumps and wheelies.}
{0x111}		{用来保存美容糖果的盒子}																{きのみブレンダーで　つくった　ポロックを　ほぞんする　いれもの}					{A case for holding POKéBLOCKS made with a BERRY BLENDER. It releases one POKéBLOCK when shaken.}
{0x112}		{德邦公司社长给儿子戴戈的信}															{デボンしゃちょう　から　あずかった　てがみ}										{An extremely important letter to STEVEN from the PRESIDENT of the DEVON CORPORATION.}
{0x113}		{去南之孤岛的船票}																		{みなみのことうへ　いく　ふねの　チケット}											{The ticket required for sailing on a ferry to a distant southern island. It features a drawing of an island.}
{0x114}		{据说蕴藏远古力量的红色的闪闪发光的玉}													{おおむかしの　ちからが　こめられている　という　あかく　かがやく　たま}			{An orb that glows red. It is said to contain an incredible power from ancient times.}
{0x115}		{据说蕴藏远古力量的蓝色的闪闪发光的玉}													{おおむかしの　ちからが　こめられている　という　あおく　かがやく　たま}			{An orb that glows blue. It is said to contain an incredible power from ancient times.}
{0x116}		{废弃船上发现的道具}																	{すてられぶねの　なかで　みつけた　どうぐ}											{A device used to search for life-forms in water. It looks too difficult to use.}
{0x117}		{保护眼睛免受沙漠中沙暴伤害的护眼罩}													{さばくの　すなあらしから　めを　まもってくれる　すてきな　ゴーグル}				{A pair of protective goggles. They enable a TRAINER to travel through even desert sandstorms.}
{0x118}		{坠落在流星瀑布中的陨石}																{りゅうせいのたきに　おちていた　いんせき}											{A meteorite that fell from space onto MT. MOON long ago. It is very lumpy and hard.}
{0x119}		{废弃船中房间的钥匙}																	{すてられぶねの　へやに　はいる　ための　カギ}										{A key that opens the door to Room 1 inside the ABANDONED SHIP. It is old and looks easily broken.}
{0x11A}		{废弃船中房间的钥匙}																	{すてられぶねの　へやに　はいる　ための　カギ}										{A key that opens the door to Room 2 inside the ABANDONED SHIP. It is old and looks easily broken.}
{0x11B}		{废弃船中房间的钥匙}																	{すてられぶねの　へやに　はいる　ための　カギ}										{A key that opens the door to Room 4 inside the ABANDONED SHIP. It is old and looks easily broken.}
{0x11C}		{废弃船中房间的钥匙}																	{すてられぶねの　へやに　はいる　ための　カギ}										{A key that opens the door to Room 6 inside the ABANDONED SHIP. It is old and looks easily broken.}
{0x11D}		{废弃船中仓库的钥匙}																	{すてられぶねの　そうこに　はいる　ための　カギ}									{A key that opens the storage hold inside the ABANDONED SHIP. It is old and looks easily broken.}
{0x11E}		{生活在远古海底的宠物（化石花）的化石}													{おおむかし　かいていで　くらしていた　ポケモンの　カセキと　いわれている}			{A fossil of an ancient, seafloor- dwelling POKéMON. It appears to be part of a plant root.}
{0x11F}		{生活在远古海底的宠物（化石蝎）的化石}													{おおむかし　かいていで　くらしていた　ポケモンの　カセキと　いわれている}			{A fossil of an ancient, seafloor- dwelling POKéMON. It appears to be part of a claw.}
{0x120}		{德邦制造的用来发现隐藏宠物（变色龙）的特制品}											{みえない　ポケモンに　はんのうして　おとをだす　デボンの　とくせいひん}			{A scope that signals the presence of any unseeable POKéMON. It is made by the DEVON CORP.}
{0x121}		{技能机器０１}																			{てきに　だいダメージを　あたえるが　こうげきを　うけると　ひるんでしまう}			{An attack that is executed last. The user flinches if hit beforehand.}
{0x122}		{技能机器０２}																			{ながく　するどい　ツメで　てきを　ひっかけて　こうげきする}						{Sharp, huge claws hook and slash the foe quickly and with great power.}
{0x123}		{技能机器０３}																			{ちょうおんぱ　こうげきで　てきを　こんらんさせる　ことがある}						{An attack with a pulsing blast of water. It may also confuse the foe.}
{0x124}		{技能机器０４}																			{せいしんを　しゅうちゅう　させて　とくこうと　とくぼうを　あげる}					{The user focuses its mind to raise the SP. ATK and SP. DEF stats.}
{0x125}		{技能机器０５}																			{ほえて　てきを　にがす　てきが　にげると　せんとうは　おわる}						{The foe is made to switch out with an ally. In the wild, the battle ends.}
{0x126}		{技能机器０６}																			{じょじょに　ダメージが　ふえる　もうどくを　てきに　あたえる}						{A move that badly poisons the foe. Its poison damage worsens every turn.}
{0x127}		{技能机器０７}																			{あられを　ふらして　こおりタイプ　いがいに　ダメージを　あたえる}					{A hailstorm lasting five turns damages all POKéMON except the ICE-type.}
{0x128}		{技能机器０８}																			{からだを　きたえて　こうげきと　ぼうぎょの　ちからを　あげる}						{The user bulks up its body to boost both its ATTACK and DEFENSE stats.}
{0x129}		{技能机器０９}																			{タネを　２ー５かい　れんぞくで　はっしゃして　てきを　こうげきする}				{The user shoots seeds at the foe. Two to five seeds are shot at once.}
{0x12A}		{技能机器１０}																			{ポケモンによって　てきに　あたえる　ダメージの　りょうが　へんかする}				{An attack that varies in type and intensity depending on the user.}
{0x12B}		{技能机器１１}																			{５ターンの　あいだ　ほのおタイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}						{The sun blazes for five turns, powering up FIRE-type moves.}
{0x12C}		{技能机器１２}																			{あいてを　おこらせて　こうげきわざ　しか　だせない　ように　する}					{The foe is taunted into a rage that allows it to use only attack moves.}
{0x12D}		{技能机器１３}																			{れいきを　はっしゃして　てきを　こうげきする　こおらせる　ことがある}				{The foe is struck with an icy beam. It may freeze the foe solid.}
{0x12E}		{技能机器１４}																			{ゆきを　つよいかぜに　のせて　こうげきする　こおらせる　ことがある}				{The foe is blasted with a blizzard. It may freeze the foe solid.}
{0x12F}		{技能机器１５}																			{ダメージは　おおきいが　つかうと　つぎのターン　うごけなく　なってしまう}			{A severely damaging attack that makes the user rest on the next turn.}
{0x130}		{技能机器１６}																			{ひかりのかべを　つくり　とくこうの　ダメージを　よわめる}							{A wall of light cuts damage from SP. ATK attacks for five turns.}
{0x131}		{技能机器１７}																			{そのターンの　こうげきを　うけないが　れんぞくして　だすと　しっぱいしやすい}		{Enables the user to evade all attacks. It may fail if used in succession.}
{0x132}		{技能机器１８}																			{５ターンの　あいだ　みずタイプの　わざのいりょくが　あがる}						{A heavy rain falls for five turns, powering up WATER- type moves.}
{0x133}		{技能机器１９}																			{あたえた　ダメージの　はんぶんの　たいりょくを　かいふく　できる}					{A harsh attack that absorbs half the damage it inflicted to restore HP.}
{0x134}		{技能机器２０}																			{ふしぎな　ちからに　まもられて　とくしゅ　じょうたいに　ならない}					{It protects the user's party from all status problems for five turns.}
{0x135}		{技能机器２１}																			{ポケモンが　なついて　いないほど　あたえる　ダメージが　あがる}					{This attack move grows more powerful the less the user likes its TRAINER.}
{0x136}		{技能机器２２}																			{１ターンめで　ひかりを　きゅうしゅうして　つぎの　ターンに　こうげきする}			{A 2-turn move that blasts the foe with absorbed energy in the 2nd turn.}
{0x137}		{技能机器２３}																			{かたいシッポで　こうげき　てきの　ぼうぎょを　さげる　ことがある}					{An attack with a steel-hard tail. It may lower the foe's DEFENSE stat.}
{0x138}		{技能机器２４}																			{でんげきを　あびせる　あたった　てきを　まひさせる　ことがある}					{A strong electrical attack that may also leave the foe paralyzed.}
{0x139}		{技能机器２５}																			{かみなりを　おとす　あたった　てきを　まひさせる　ことがある}						{A brutal lightning attack that may also leave the foe paralyzed.}
{0x13A}		{技能机器２６}																			{じめんを　つよく　ゆらす　とんでいる　てきいがいに　だいダメージを　あたえる}		{An earthquake that strikes all POKéMON in battle excluding the user.}
{0x13B}		{技能机器２７}																			{ポケモンが　なついて　いるほど　あたえる　ダメージが　あがる}						{This attack move grows more powerful the more the user likes its TRAINER.}
{0x13C}		{技能机器２８}																			{１ターンめで　じめんに　もぐり　つぎのターンに　てきを　こうげきする}				{An attack that hits on the 2nd turn. Can also be used to exit dungeons.}
{0x13D}		{技能机器２９}																			{つよい　ねんりきを　だす　てきの　とくぼうを　さげる　ことがある}					{A strong telekinetic attack. It may also lower the foe's SP. DEF stat.}
{0x13E}		{技能机器３０}																			{くろいかたまりを　なげる　てきの　とくぼうを　さげる　ことがある}					{A shadowy blob is hurled at the foe. May also lower the foe's SP. DEF.}
{0x13F}		{技能机器３１}																			{ひかりのかべ　などを　こわして　てきに　　　ダメージを　あたえられる}				{An attack that also breaks any barrier like LIGHT SCREEN and REFLECT.}
{0x140}		{技能机器３２}																			{ぶんしんを　つくって　てきを　まどわせて　かいひりつを　あげる}					{The user creates illusory copies of itself to raise its evasiveness.}
{0x141}		{技能机器３３}																			{ひかりのかべを　つくり　ぶつり　こうげきの　ダメージを　よわめる}					{A wall of light cuts damage from physical attacks for five turns.}
{0x142}		{技能机器３４}																			{ぜったいに　よけられない　すばやさで　てきに　でんげきを　あびせる}				{A rapid jolt of electricity strikes the foe. It can't be evaded.}
{0x143}		{技能机器３５}																			{ほのおを　まきちらす　あたった　てきを　やけどさせる　ことがある}					{The foe is scorched with intense flames. The foe may suffer a burn.}
{0x144}		{技能机器３６}																			{ヘドロを　なげつける　あたった　てきに　どくを　あたえることが　ある}				{Filthy sludge is hurled at the foe. It may poison the target.}
{0x145}		{技能机器３７}																			{すなあらしを　おこして　まいターン　てきに　ダメージを　あたえる}					{A 5-turn sandstorm that damages all types except ROCK, GROUND, and STEEL.}
{0x146}		{技能机器３８}																			{だいの　もじで　すべてを　やきつくす　こうげき　やけどさせる　ことがある}			{The foe is hit with an intense flame. It may leave the target with a burn.}
{0x147}		{技能机器３９}																			{いわで　てきの　うごきを　ふうじて　こうげき　すばやさを　さげられる}				{Boulders are hurled at the foe. It also lowers the foe's SPEED if it hits.}
{0x148}		{技能机器４０}																			{すばやい　うごきで　　ぜったいに　よけられない　こうげきを　する}					{An extremely fast attack against one target. It can't be evaded.}
{0x149}		{技能机器４１}																			{てきが　おなじわざを　れんぞくで　だせない　ようにする}							{It enrages the foe, making it incapable of using the same move successively.}
{0x14A}		{技能机器４２}																			{どく　まひ　やけどのとき　こうげきの　ちからを　あげる　ことが　できる}			{An attack that is boosted if user is burned, poisoned, or paralyzed.}
{0x14B}		{技能机器４３}																			{たたかう　ばしょに　より　てきに　あたえる　ついか　こうかが　かわる}				{An attack that may have an additional effect that varies with the terrain.}
{0x14C}		{技能机器４４}																			{２ターンねむり　からだの　いじょうと　たいりょくを　ぜんかいふく　する}			{The user sleeps for two turns to fully restore HP and heal any status problem.}
{0x14D}		{技能机器４５}																			{オスなら　メスに　メスなら　オスに　わざが　だしにくくなる}						{If it is the other gender, the foe is made infatuated and unlikely to attack.}
{0x14E}		{技能机器４６}																			{こうげきちゅうに　すきを　みて　てきが　もっている　どうぐを　ぬすむ}				{An attack that may take the foe's held item if the user isn't holding one.}
{0x14F}		{技能机器４７}																			{かたいつばさを　おおきく　ひろげて　そのまま　てきに　たいあたりする}				{The foe is hit with wings of steel. It may also raise the user's DEFENSE.}
{0x150}		{技能机器４８}																			{わざを　だした　ターンに　じぶんと　てきの　とくせいを　いれかえる}				{The user employs its psychic power to swap abilities with the foe.}
{0x151}		{技能机器４９}																			{てきが　つかおうとした　わざを　うばって　じぶんに　つかう}						{Steals the effects of the foe's healing or status- changing move.}
{0x152}		{技能机器５０}																			{フルパワーで　こうげき　できるが　とくこうが　ガクッと　さがってしまう}			{An intense attack that also sharply reduces the user's SP. ATK stat.}
{0x153}		{秘传机器０１}																			{カマや　ツメなどの　するどいもので　てきを　きりつけて　こうげきする}				{A basic attack. It can be used to cut down thin trees and grass.}
{0x154}		{秘传机器０２}																			{１ターンめで　そらへとび　つぎの　ターンに　てきを　こうげきする}					{A 2-turn move that hits on the 2nd turn. Use it to fly to any known town.}
{0x155}		{秘传机器０３}																			{みずに　なみを　おこし　それを　ものすごい　ちからで　たたきつける}				{A big wave crashes down on the foe. Can also be used for crossing water.}
{0x156}		{秘传机器０４}																			{ぜんしんに　ものすごい　ちからを　ためこみ　てきを　こうげきする}					{The foe is slugged at maximum power. Can also be used to move boulders.}
{0x157}		{秘传机器０５}																			{つよい　ひかりで　めを　くらませて　てきの　めいちゅうりつを　さげる}				{A blast of light that cuts the foe's accuracy. It also illuminates caves.}
{0x158}		{秘传机器０６}																			{いわをもくだく　ちからで　てきの　ぼうぎょを　さげる　ことがある}					{An attack that may also cut DEFENSE. It can also smash cracked boulders.}
{0x159}		{秘传机器０７}																			{たきを　さかのぼるような　いきおいで　てきに　とっしんする}						{A powerful charge attack. It can also be used to climb a waterfall.}
{0x15A}		{秘传机器０８}																			{１ターンめで　みずに　　もぐり　つぎのターンで　てきを　こうげきする}				{The user dives underwater on the first turn and strikes next turn.}
{0x15B}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x15C}		{}																						{}																					{}
{0x15D}		{商店的店员拜托的转交给大木博士的物品}													{ショップの　てんいんから　たのまれた　おとどけもの　オーキドはかせに　わたす}		{A parcel to be delivered to PROF. OAK from VIRIDIAN CITY's POKéMON MART.}
{0x15E}		{音色纯美的笛子，用来叫醒沉睡中的宠物（卡比兽）}										{きれいな　ねいろの　ふえ　ねている　ポケモンが　きくと　とびおきる}				{A flute that is said to instantly awaken any POKéMON. It has a lovely tone.}
{0x15F}		{红莲岛道馆的钥匙}																		{グレンじま　ジムの　いりぐちを　あける　カギ}										{The key to CINNABAR ISLAND GYM's front door. It is colored red and decorated.}
{0x160}		{用来在奇迹·自行车店交换折叠式自行车的票据}											{ミラクル・サイクルで　おりたたみ　じてんしゃと　こうかん　できる　かみ}			{Take this voucher to the BIKE SHOP in CERULEAN CITY and exchange it for a bicycle.}
{0x161}		{裟福利狩猎区园长丢失的金色假牙}														{サファリゾーンの　えんちょうが　おとした　きんいろの　いれば}						{A set of false teeth lost by the SAFARI ZONE'S WARDEN. It makes his smile sparkle.}
{0x162}		{封存有古代宠物（化石翼龙）的后代的信息的石头}											{こだい　ポケモンの　いでんし　じょうほうが　とじこめられている　いし}				{A piece of amber that contains the genes of an ancient POKéMON. It is clear with a reddish tint.}
{0x163}		{喜禄福公司大楼中各扇门的钥匙}															{カードで　できた　カギ　シルフカンパニー　ビルの　ドアロックを　はずせる}			{A card-type key that unlocks doors in SILPH CO.'s HEAD OFFICE in SAFFRON CITY.}
{0x164}		{火箭队的藏身所的电梯的钥匙}															{ロケットだん　アジトの　エレベーターを　うごかす　ことが　できる　カギ}			{A key that operates the elevator in TEAM ROCKET's HIDEOUT. It bears the TEAM ROCKET logo.}
{0x165}		{生活在远古大海中的宠物（菊石兽）的贝壳的碎片}											{おおむかし　うみに　すんでいた　ポケモンの　かいがらの　いちぶ}					{A fossil of an ancient, seafloor- dwelling POKéMON. It appears to be part of a seashell.}
{0x166}		{生活在远古大海中的宠物（万年虫）的甲壳的碎片}											{おおむかし　うみに　すんでいた　ポケモンの　こうらの　いちぶ}						{A fossil of an ancient, seafloor- dwelling POKéMON. It appears to be part of a shell.}
{0x167}		{喜禄福公司制造的可以看到肉眼无法看到的东西（嘎拉嘎拉的魂魄）的观测镜}					{めに　みえない　ものを　みられる　スコープ　シルフ　カンパニーせい}				{A scope that makes unseeable POKéMON visible. It is made by SILPH CO.}
{0x168}		{比跑鞋更快的折叠式自行车}																{おりたたみの　じてんしゃ　ランニングシューズより　はやく　はしる}					{A folding bicycle that allows faster movement than the RUNNING SHOES.}
{0x169}		{可随时查看的方便的地图，还能显示出自己在地图上的位置}									{いつでも　みることが　できる　べんりな　ちず　じぶんの　いちも　わかる}			{A very convenient map that can be viewed anytime. It even shows your present location.}
{0x16A}		{地图上使用，显示出可以再次战斗的训练员的状态，充满电需走100步}							{たたかえる　トレーナーを　おしえてくれる　きかい　じゅうでんして　つかう}			{A device that indicates TRAINERS who want to battle. The battery charges while traveling.}
{0x16B}		{记录对各地名人的所见所闻的机器}														{ゆうめいな　じんぶつの　じょうほうを　いつでも　みなおすことが　できる}			{A device that enables you to recall what you've heard and seen about famous people.}
{0x16C}		{保管技能机器的箱子}																	{わざマシンを　ほかんする　べんりな　いれもの}										{A case that holds TMs and HMs. It is attached to the BAG's compartment for important items.}
{0x16D}		{保管树果的袋子}																		{きのみを　ほぞんする　べんりな　いれもの}											{A pouch for carrying BERRIES. It is attached to the BAG's compartment for important items.}
{0x16E}		{播放教育节目，使训练员快速入门的电视机}												{トレーナーの　やくにたつ　ばんぐみを　みることが　できる　テレビ}					{A television set that is tuned to a program with useful tips for novice TRAINERS.}
{0x16F}		{去１～３岛的船票}																		{１のしまと　２のしまと　３のしまを　いどうする　ふねに　のれる}					{A pass for ferries between ONE, TWO, and THREE ISLAND. It has a drawing of three islands.}
{0x170}		{去４～７岛的船票}																		{クチバシティと　ななしまを　いどうする　ふねに　のれる}							{A pass for ferries between VERMILION and the SEVII ISLANDS. It features a drawing of a rainbow.}
{0x171}		{老奶奶煮的清香的润喉茶}																{おばあさんが　いれた　おいしい　おちゃ　かわきを　うるおす}						{An aromatic tea prepared by an old lady. It will slake even the worst thirst.}
{0x172}		{去中央岩石的船票}																		{へそのいわへ　いくために　ひつような　ふねの　チケット}							{A ticket required to board the ship to NAVEL ROCK. It glows with a mystic light.}
{0x173}		{去诞生岛的船票}																		{たんじょうのしまへ　いくために　ひつような　ふねの　チケット}						{A ticket required to board the ship to BIRTH ISLAND. It glows beautifully.}
{0x174}		{用来放置树果粉的瓶子}																	{きのみクラッシュで　できた　きのみの　こなを　ほぞんする　いれもの}				{A jar for storing BERRY POWDER made using a BERRY CRUSHER.}
{0x175}		{表现热情的美丽的宝石，发出闪闪的红光}													{じょうねつを　あらわす　うつくしい　ほうせき　あかく　ひかり　かがやく}			{An exquisitely beautiful gem that has a red glow. It symbolizes passion.}
{0x176}		{表现真诚的美丽的宝石，发出闪闪的蓝光}													{せいじつを　あらわす　うつくしい　ほうせき　あおく　ひかり　かがやく}				{An exquisitely beautiful gem that has a blue glow. It symbolizes honesty.}
{0x177}		{形状和熔岩团的纹章相同的金属制品}														{マグマだんの　マークと　おなじ　かたちを　した　メダルの　ようなもの}				{}
{0x178}		{记录了去某个岛屿（极遥孤岛）的海路的古代海图}											{ある　しまへの　かいろを　しるして　ある　ふるぼけた　うみの　ちず}				{}
